Contact

1209@holbertonstudents.com

www.linkedin.com/in/lh1008 (LinkedIn) github.com/lh1008 (Portfolio) lh1008.github.io/ (Personal)

Top Skills

Support Engineers
C (Programming Language)
Software Development

Languages

Español (Native or Bilingual) Inglés (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

EF SET Certificate

Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python)

EF SET English Certificate 94/100 (C1 Advanced)

Python Data Structures

Publications

Dynamic and Static Libraries in Linux What happens when you type Is -I in the shell

Python3: Mutable, Immutable... everything is object!

Luis Herrera

Support Engineer at ADDI & Monero Outreach Enthusiast Colombia

Summary

Cryptocurrency privacy-focused Monero (XMR) enthusiast. Focused in open-source software GNU/Linux operating systems since 2016.

Studied Software Engineering foundations at Holberton School Colombia with a high passion for blockchain technology. Entrepreneur, adventurer, and eager to develop code for our world.

Experience in C, Python, and JavaScript programming languages, hand-coded HTML and CSS with MySQL database integration.

Blog: https://lh1008.medium.com/

Experience

Addi

Support Engineer December 2021 - Present (3 years 4 months) Colombia

- Client technical support: resolve CX (customer experience team) requests, workflows, user flow, and app issues, analyze technical client logs, error detection, request escalation, and training.
- Engineering Support: request escalation, detect/open incidents (analiyze impact), share logs, stats.
- Engineering projects: built automated API tool project, automation scripting.

Software: Slack, PostgreSQL, Kustomer, Mezmo (LogDNA), LogRocket, Grafana schedule handler, incidents, and log analyzer), Databricks (automated cluster management; graphical command-line interface), Sublime (IDE), Python, PostgreSQL, Notion (documentation), Asana (task management), Lucidchart (diagrams).

Development: SCRUM (sprints)

Monero

Communication Work-group Coordinator July 2018 - Present (6 years 9 months)

Colombia

- Workgroup communication coordinator
- Project task management coordinator
- Junior SysOps/DevOps maintainer

Blockchain Labb

Software Engineer

September 2020 - September 2021 (1 year 1 month)

- Development Coordinator: organize and coordinate development working directly with the developers

to follow the company's needs and blockchain integrations.

- Code Reviewer: check the developer's code and make the tryouts.
- Repository and Server Maintainer: maintain, review, and check repository's commits and accept

changes. SysOps/DevOps server maintainer.

- Programming Languages: Vuejs, Nuxtjs, Nodejs.

Emcali - Telecomunicaciones

Database Analyst

September 2016 - February 2018 (1 year 6 months)

Valle del Cauca, Colombia

- Database Analyst: Microsoft Excel
- GIS (Geographic Information System) Analyst: GEOVISOR/MapInfo software
- Recruiter: assistant training
- Software: OPEN-SmartFlex utility software

Productos Vrinda

Business Development Administrator

February 2013 - May 2016 (3 years 4 months)

Colombia

Production and service manager. My responsibilities were to cover the customer service area, staff planning, purchase, storage, and sales. I had to contact suppliers, make the financial accounting control, have resource optimization, and comply with quality standards and regulations of the food and beverage sector.

Servinformación S.A.

Georeferencer

February 2010 - February 2013 (3 years 1 month)

Colombia

Homologate national property number in the company's databases to the EMCALI subscriber. I also made routing fieldwork through Geographic Information Systems (GIS). Geographic software layer control, collector supervisor, and location coordinates updates. Software: MapInfo, Excel, Access.

Education

Holberton School Software Engineer, Programming · (2019 - 2021)

Udemy Academy
Web Designer, Web Development · (2017 - 2018)

Universidad Libre Seccional Cali Economics, Economy · (2017)